Fried, John H. E.; Papers ger014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Reprints and typescripts by other authors, 11; 154 file folders
  - Paech, Norman. "Nuremberg and the Nuclear Question", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 35)
  - Paech, Norman, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 36)
  - Paige, Glenn D. "Nonviolent Alternatives in International Studies: Five Questions", 1985; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 37)
  - Paust, Jordan J. "Restraints on Development, Export and Use", 1978; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 38)
  - Paust, Jordan J., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 39)
  - Peretz, David, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 40)
  - Petersen, Glenn. "Termination of U.S. Trusteeship in Micronesia", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 41)
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility, Inc. "Nuclear Power and Weapons Packet", 1977 June; Mimeographed booklet (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 42)
  - Pradhan, Hargovinda Singh. Untitled typescript, Undated (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 43)
  - Remond, René. "Les problems au lendemain de la Libération", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 44)
  - Robertson, A. H., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 45)
  - Robertson, Thomas. "Challenging Presidential First Use of Nuclear Weapons: Issues of Justiciability", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 46)
  - Robinson, A. N. R., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 47)
  - Robinson, Jacob. "Code of Offences Against Peace and Security of Mankind", 1954 November 17; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 48)
  - Röling, Bert V. A., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 49)
  - Roff, Sue Rabbitt, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 50)
  - Rosas, Allan, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 51)
  - Rosner, Gabriella. "The Historical Background of Financing International Organizations", 1962 October; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 52)
  - Rostow, Eugene V. "The Great Nuclear Debate", 1982 April 23; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 53)
  - Rubin, Alfred P., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 54)
  - Salzberg, John. "The United Nations and the Bangladesh Crisis. A Case Study of UN Capability to Deal with Massive Violations of Human Rights", 1972 March 10; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 55)
  - Schachter, Oscar, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 56)
  - Schöneburg, Karl-Heinz. "Der nazifaschistische Staat, sein Recht, nazifaschistische Staats- und Rechtsauffassungen", 1986 December; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 57)
  - Schwarzenberger, G., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 58)
  - Schwarzschild, Steven S. "Disengagement or Engagement in the Near East", 1975 August 28; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 59)
  - Schwarzschild, Steven S. "'Nuremberg' Is Always Valid", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 60)
  - Schwarzschild, Steven S., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 61)
  - Schwelb, Egon, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 62)
  - Shibato, Shingo. "For Human Survival - The Tasks of Marxism to Prevent Nuclear Extinction", 1979; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 63)
  - Sirefman, Josef P., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 64)
  - Snyder, Earl A., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 65)
  - Somerville, John, Undated; reprints, clippings (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 66)
  - Somerville, John. The Crisis. A Play in Four Acts, Undated (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 67)
  - Stegenda, James A., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 68)
  - Steininger, Peter Alfons. "Vorwort", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 69)
  - Stoessinger, John G, Undated; Clipping (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 70)
  - Stuby, Gerhard, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 71)
  - Szilard, Leo, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 72)
  - Vacca, Roberto. "Demographic and Economic Factors Affecting Aggression and Violence", 1978; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 73)
  - Valticos, Nicolas. "Decisions of International Organizations: Effectiveness in Member States", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 74)
  - Voicu, Ioan, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 75)
  - Warren, Earl, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 76)
  - Weisskopf, Victor F., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 77)
  - Weston, Burns H., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 78)
  - Williams, William Appleman, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 79)
  - Wittner, Lawrence S., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 80)
  - Woetzel, Robert K., Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 81)
  - Wright, Quincy, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 82)
  - Wyler, Julius, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 83)
  - Zerner, Ruth, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 84)
- Files on various topics, 12; 143 file folders
  This series contains newspapers clippings, magazine articles and other materials collected by Fried on topics of interest such as: nuclear weapons and disarmament, militarism, international law, and human rights. The collection also contains materials on countries and regions, such as: Cuba, Chile, Vietnam, Korea, Israel, Palestine, Iran, Micronesia and the Soviet Union.
  - Afghanistan, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1)
  - America, general, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 2)
  - Angola / South Africa, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Anti-Jewish Legislation in Europe and North Africa, imposed or inspired by National Socialist Germany, 1948 (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4-5)
  - Anti-Nuclear Quotations, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 6-8)
  - Anti-War Protesters, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 9)
  - Arab / Israeli Conflicts, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 10)
  - Bangladesh / Pakistan, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 11)
  - Bush, George Herbert Walker, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - Cambodia, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 13)
  - Capitalism, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 14)
  - Carter, Jimmy, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Central America, Caribbean, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 16)
  - Centrality of International Law (Brighton Conference), 1988 (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 17)
  - Chemical and Biological Warfare, Undated (Box 28 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 18)
  - Civil Rights / Segregation, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1)
  - Cold War / Militarization of Society, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 2)
  - Communism, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Communism - Early Post World War II, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4)
  - Conventions on Excessively Injurious Weapons, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 5)
  - Cuba / Cuban Missile Crisis, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Cyprus, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 7)
  - Czechoslovakia, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 8)
  - Disarmament, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 9-11)
  - Egypt, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 13)
  - El Salvador, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 14)
  - Fondation Internationale Lelio Basso, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Ford, Gerald, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 16)
  - France - Post World War II, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 17)
  - Functional Regionalism, militarism, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 18)
  - Germany - Post World War II, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 19)
  - Germany's Way to Defeat - World War I., Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 20)
  - Gorbachev, Mikhail, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 21)
  - Green Party, Germany, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 22)
  - Grenada, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 23)
  - Guatemala, Undated (Box 29 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 24)
  - Holocaust, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1)
  - Human Rights, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 2-3)
  - Human Rights - Rights of the Child, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4)
  - International Labour Office - publications, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 5)
  - International Law, general, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 6-7)
  - International Law - Law of Warfare, 1914 August (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 8)
  - International Law - Law of Warfare, U.S. Dept. of the Army, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 9)
  - International Law - Military, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 10)
  - International Law - Presidential Power - War Powers Act, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 11)
  - International Law - Teaching of, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - International Law - Terrorism, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 13)
  - International Law - United Nations, Undated (Box 30 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 14-15)
  - International Law - World Courts, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1)
  - Iran, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 2)
  - Iran hostage situation, 1979 (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Israel, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4-5)
  - Japan, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Jewish Agency for Israel, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 7)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 8)
  - Judaica, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 9)
  - Kennedy, John F., Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 10)
  - Kissinger, Henry, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 11)
  - Koch, Edward (Mayor, New York City), Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - Korea, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 13)
  - Lebanon, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 14)
  - Libya, attacks on, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Mauritius, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 16)
  - Micronesia - Palau, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 17)
  - Micronesia - Palau - Agreement with U.S. government, Undated (Box 31 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 18)
  - Middle East, general, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1)
  - Militarism, general, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 2)
  - Militarism - Post World War II Germany, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Militarism - U.S., Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4-6)
  - Multilingual Glossary of Military Terms, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 7)
  - National Study Committee on Vietnam, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 8)
  - NATO, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 9)
  - Nazi war criminals, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 10)
  - Neutron bomb, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 11)
  - New Economic Order, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - Nicaragua, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 13)
  - Nixon, Richard M., Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 14)
  - Non-Governmental Organizations (NGOs), Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Nuclear Arms Race, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 16)
  - Nuclear Deterrence, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 17)
  - Nuclear Free Zones, Undated (Box 32 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 18)
  - Nuclear war, general, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1-3)
  - Nuclear war - Accidental, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4-5)
  - Nuclear War - Medical & Environmental Consequences, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Nuclear War - U.N. Prohibition, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 7)
  - Nuclear Weapons & International Law, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 8)
  - Nuclear Weapons - First Use of, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 9-10)
  - Nuclear Weapons - Germany, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 11)
  - Nuclear Weapons - Latin America, Undated (Box 33 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - Nuclear Weapons - Star Wars Program, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1-2)
  - Nuclear Weapons - U.S. bases, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 3)
  - Nuremberg, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4)
  - Palestinians, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 5)
  - Panama, U.S. invasion of, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Papal encyclicals, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 7)
  - The Philippines, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 8)
  - Political philosophies, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 9)
  - Reagan, Ronald (policies), Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 10)
  - Right to Peace, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 11)
  - Right to Peace - U.N. publications, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - Scientists' Institute for Public Information, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 13)
  - Soviet Militarism, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 14)
  - S.S. Mayaguez, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Switzerland without an army, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 16)
  - Technology, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 17)
  - Thailand, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 18)
  - Tokyo War Crimes Trial, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 19)
  - Truman, Harry S., Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 20)
  - Tunisia, Undated (Box 34 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 21)
  - UNITAR, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 1)
  - United Nations, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 2)
  - U.S. economy, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 3)
  - U.S. foreign policy, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 4-5)
  - U.S. / Soviet relations, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 6)
  - Vietnam / Southeast Asia, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 7-10)
  - Visually Structured Books, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 11)
  - War, militarism, Nazism, 1945-1946 (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 12)
  - W.E.B. Dubois Memorial Park, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 13)
  - Westmoreland, General William C., Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 14)
  - World War II, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 15)
  - Yugoslavia, Undated (Box 35 (12-Files on various topics), Folder 16)
- Periodicals, 13; 7 file folders
  Several incomplete sets of periodicals, most containing annotations by Fried were retained in the collection.
  - Arms Control Today - scattered issues, 1977-1983 (Box 36 (13-Periodicals), Folder 1)
  - The Defense Monitor - scattered issues, 1974-1989 (Box 36 (13-Periodicals), Folder 2)
  - Disarmament - scattered issues, 1978; 1983 (Box 36 (13-Periodicals), Folder 3)
  - Dokumentarische Information - scattered issues, Undated (Box 36 (13-Periodicals), Folder 4-5)
  - F.A.S. Newsletter / F.A.S. Public Interest Report - scattered issues, Undated (Box 36 (13-Periodicals), Folder 6)
  - The United Nations Review, Vol. III, No. 2, 4, 8, 1943 (Box 36 (13-Periodicals), Folder 7)
  - The Washington Spectator - scattered issues, 1980-1989 (Box 36 (13-Periodicals), Folder 8)
- Series 14: Pamphlets, 4 archive boxes, unsorted (Box 37-40 (John H. E. Fried Papers))
  The collection of pamphlets is extensive and contains pamphlets on most of the subject areas in which Fried was interested. These include: Vietnam and Southeast Asia, Nuclear war and disarmament, the United Nations and treaties, Somalia, Bangladesh, Cuba, Chile, Korea, Israel, Palestine and the Middle East, the Soviet Union, Human Rights, Rights of the Child and Women's Rights.